

About

My name is Plamen Kolev and I am a Newcastle, England based developer specializing in web application development, system automation and web app deployment. I enjoy playing with emerging technologies and stay up to date with thech trends.

In the past three years I have gained knowledge in Perl, Bash, Unix-based operating systems, python for web development and PHP.

Work Experience

Software Engineer Intern, Intel Corporation

August 2015 - September 2016

Worked on the high perormance security projects. Created automated tests through bash, Perl and the in-house tools. I also developed scripts to automate product integration and deployment. Worked with a large multi-national team

Interviewer, Populus Data Solutions

**April 2014 - June 2015** 

Conducted national studies across Britain on sociopolitical issues

Lead Graphic Designer, Ivesto Company

**September 2012 - June 2013** 

Worked full time as a website manager and designer where I had the opportunity to improve the user experience and maintain the two websites of the company.

Education

BSc. Computer Science, Newcastle University

**September 2013 - Present** 

Website plamen-k.github.io

Email p.kolev22@gmail.com

Github https://github.com/plamen-k

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/plamen-kolev-465915a7

**Projects** 

Neven Body care

5 August - 28 August 2016

Created a website for the neven brand

**Secure Coding Presentation** 

5 May 2016

Presenter at Lester College conference that taught the importance of writing secure code

Lloyds Banking

September 2014 - March 2015

Developed and designed a website with restful API that hooks to an Android application for the british bank Lloyds. The product was produced as part of a team.

HackNE Hackathon

31 October 2014

Co-organized a hackathon in the North East, United Kingdom backed by Major League Hacking EU. Created the website for the event, PR and print design materials.

**PAConsulting** 

**12 February 2014** 

Developed an environmental friendly hardware & software solution with the Raspberry Pi that involves predictive light automation and controll.

Webloz

18 April 2012

Webloz -national competition for web development finalist

Object-oriented programing, design & development of software. Web design & construction: delivery and

consumption of web content, database technologies.

Computer Architecture: Parallel Computer

Architectures

Low-level programing. Software Engineering - principles and lifecycle, scalability and maintnance.

Team projects, working as part of a group.